Contact

+351 964 104 811 (Mobile) miguelsaraiva81@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/miguelsaraiva (LinkedIn)

www.scrumalliance.org/community/ profile/msaraivasa (Other) www.outsystems.com/ profile/87440/ (Other)

Top Skills

Scrum

Liferay

OutSystems

Languages

Portuguese (Native or Bilingual) English (Native or Bilingual) French (Elementary)

Certifications

Certified Scrum Professional® Product Owner Liferay Developer Training OutSystems Associate Developer Certified Scrum Professional® Liferay System Administrator Training

Publications

Estudo de Sistemas de Detecção e Prevenção de Intrusões - Uma Abordagem Open Source

Miguel Saraiva Sampaio

Senior Consultant at Edge Portugal

Lisbon Area, Portugal

Summary

More than a decade successfully implementing IT Projects (Agile, Java/Liferay and OutSystems) now developing a new set of skills in management and a true believer in best practices / premium software architecture. Always implementing People First mindset and available to help and mentor.

A Computer Science and Communications Engineering Degree and a Software Development Agile Methodologies Post-Graduation.

Agilist to the bone, avid practitioner and co-organizer / co-chair of Agile Portugal community events.

Certified Scrum Master, Product Owner, Developer, Professional ScrumMaster and Professional Product Owner by the Scrum Alliance.

Liferay Certified Training (Back in 2011) and OutSystems Associate Developer (In 2017).

Experience

Edge Portugal Senior Consultant November 2019 - Present (5 months) Lisbon Area, Portugal

PwC Portugal Senior Consultant May 2019 - October 2019 (6 months) Lisbon Area, Portugal

BABEL

Development Project Leader 2019 - 2019 (less than a year)

Lisbon Area, Portugal

darwinLabs Senior Software Engineer 2014 - 2018 (4 years)

Lisbon Area, Portugal

Project Manager, Product Manager, Software Engineer, Architect and Developer in Java/Liferay and OutSystems projects.

Agile Mindset - Acting as a Scrum Master or Product Owner.

Helping managing the company growth in projects and talent.

Altran

Liferay Advanced Consultant – Software Engineer 2013 - 2013 (less than a year)

Lisbon Area, Portugal

Spread the know-how in Liferay trough the team to reach a common goal. As a Liferay focused person it was a great project for him.

AGAP2

Software Engineering Consultant (Java Analyst / Programmer) 2010 - 2013 (3 years)

Lisbon Area, Portugal

As a Consultant, has worked with JEE, in some projects with Core Features and in others with Web Features, oriented to Liferay and MVC Frameworks.

TIMwe

Liferay Software Developer 2009 - 2010 (1 year)

Lisbon Area, Portugal

Worked for several instances of Liferay Portals in the Digital Sales Team.

Wide Scope IT Engineering Consultant 2008 - 2009 (1 year) Lisbon Area, Portugal

Did consulting in several outsourcing projects.

Also integrated some of the inside projects.

Technologies Used: JEE (Java) focused on MVC frameworks like Struts.

SONAE Distribuição IT Engineer 2008 - 2008 (less than a year) Oporto Area, Portugal

IT Engineer at Sonae Distribuição also know as Modelo Continente Hipermercados.

Projects for DSI (Direcção de Sistemas de Informação).

Instituto Politécnico de Leiria Helpdesk / Computer Technician 2007 - 2007 (less than a year) Leiria Area, Portugal

Computer and User Support Unit at Computer Services - IPLeiria (Campus 2).

Education

Instituto Politécnico de Leiria

Post-Graduation, Software Development Agile Methodologies · (2011 - 2012)

Instituto Politécnico de Leiria Licentiate degree, Computer Science and Communications Engineering · (2006 - 2008)

Instituto Politécnico de Leiria

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science and Communications

Engineering · (2001 - 2006)